CSS grin a system for laying out items across a movable set of horizontal and
CSS grin 用于在网格内通过一组可移动的水平和
vertical lines inside a grid we have invisible lines that divide columns and
垂直线布置项目的系统 我们有分隔列和行的不可见线
rows the space between two parallel grid lines is known as a grid track and the
两条平行网格线之间的空间称为网格轨道，
space between four lines is known as a grid area in your HTML start with a
四行之间的空间已知 作为HTML 中的网格区域，以
parent element to serve as your grid container then all of its children will
父元素作为网格容器开始，然后它的所有子元素将
automatically become grid items let's imagine we wanted to build a website
自动成为网格项让我们想象一下
with a holy grail layout in the HTML if we have a container with five elements
，如果我们有一个容器，我们想在 HTML 中构建一个具有圣杯布局的网站
inside we'll start by setting the containers display property to grid now
里面的五个元素我们首先将容器显示属性设置为网格现在
open your app in Firefox to visualize the gridlines tracks and areas it helps
在 Firefox 中打开您的应用程序以可视化网格线轨道和区域这有助于
to imagine your website as an Excel spreadsheet in each individual cell add
将您的网站想象为每个单独的单元格中的 Excel 电子表格添加
a label that represents the element that should appear there each cell in the
一个代表元素的标签应该出现在
grid represents one fractional unit in the middle we have an advertisement the
网格中的每个单元格代表中间的一个分数单位我们有一个广告
main content and the sidebar then we have the top bar taking up three cells
主要内容和侧边栏然后我们有顶部 条在顶部占据三个单元格
on the top and a footer on the bottom notice how this represents a three by
，在底部占据一个页脚注意它如何表示一个三乘
three grid and we can use this as the value for the grid template areas
三的网格，我们可以将其用作网格模板区域
property now we need to tell the children which grid area that they take
属性的值现在我们需要告诉孩子他们占据哪个网格区域
up we can do that by providing the name to the grid area property that gives us
我们可以通过为网格区域属性提供名称来实现这一点，该属性为我们提供
the right layout but now we want to adjust the size of the rows and columns
了正确的布局，但是现在我们想要调整行和列的大小，
currently each column is taking up one third or one fractional unit of the
目前每列占用了我们可用空间的三分之一或一个小数单位
available space we can change the width of the middle column by setting it to a
可以通过将中间列设置为
fixed pixel value or change the ratio by giving it three fractional units
固定像素值来改变其宽度，或者通过给它三个小数单位
likewise we can change the height of rows using the grid template rows
来改变比率。同样，
property if we want to add spacing between our grid lines we can use the
如果我们想在网格线之间添加间距，我们可以使用网格模板行属性来改变行的高度 我们可以使用
great gap property and we can Center the children vertically or horizontally
大间隙属性，我们可以
using justify items or line items and make sure to check out the min Max and
使用对齐项目或行项目垂直或水平居中子级，并确保检查最小最大和
repeat functions to avoid duplication on larger grids this has been CSS grid and
重复功能以避免在la 上重复 rger grids 这是 CSS 网格和
100 seconds stay tuned for a full grid project in a few days and make sure to
100 秒，请继续关注几天后的完整网格项目，
hit the like button if you want to see more short videos like this thanks for
如果您想观看更多类似这样的短视频，请务必点击“赞”按钮，谢谢
watching and I will see you in the next one
观看，我们下期再见一